Then buy some nail clippers.
(まりな) 爪切り買えばいいじゃん
But I've got some.
(光石)持ってるよ 爪切り
No, I mean expensive clippers of your very own.
(まりな)違う 自分専用の高い爪切り
But those are really nice.
(光石)いいやつだから しし だって
I'd rather use a nice--
いいやつで しし! 切ったほうが…
What's wrong? You're staring off into space.
(まりな)どうしたの? 菜緒ボーッとして なお
You haven't eaten anything.
(光石) 全然弁当食ってないじゃん
I thought you were making your own lunch. Are you already sick of it?
てかお弁当作り始めたと思ったら もう飽きちゃつたの?
I overslept today.
(菜緒)今日寝坊しちゃつて (まり )ふ~ん な
Oh, sorry. What were you talking about?
あ…ごめん 何の話だっけ?
I was telling you about this.
だからこれ見てって
It says, "This Christmas is the best time in your life for having a romance.
"今年のクリスマスは 人生最大のモテ期です"
There is an excellent chance that whoever you spend Christmas Eve with
“中でもイブを一緒に過ごす相手とは 生涯を共にする可能性大!"
Oh...
へぇ~ え
I'm really happy for you, Marina.
よかったじゃんまりな
It's not me. It's you, Nao.
私じゃなくて菜緒だよ 菜緒
Really?
(菜緒)え?
Haven't you made any progress with Uehara?
うえはら ねえ上原君とは ちょっとは進展したの?
Christmas Eve's in two weeks.
イブまであと2週間だよ?
These horoscopes are never right.
この占い当たんないよ
Don't tell me again this year,
(まりな) まさかあんた 今年のイブも
"I'm going to have a family party at Daichi's house!"
“大ちゃんちでホームパーティー" とか言わないよね
A family party? You mean your families get together?
(光石)ホームパーティーって 家族ぐるみで?
Yes, exactly!
そうなの
Without fail, ever since she was seven years old
7歳の時から懲りずに ずーっとやってんの
wear Santa hats, sing "Jingle Bells",
サンタの帽子かぶって ジングルベル歌って?
-and exchange presents. -Unbelievable!
プレゼント交換して? (光石) うわありえね ー
Isn't it?
まりな)でしょ?
Since your parents aren't here this year, you can finally get away from Daichi!
今年は親がいないんだから 大ちゃんを卒業するチャンス!
Then you can make Uehara yours!
その上原久志を射止めるの! そして ひさし
I told you before, I'm not interested in Uehara.
(菜緒)だから私上原君のこと 何とも思ってないし…
-Speak of the devil. -Uehara?
(光石)あっ噂をすれば まりな)上原君!?
Nao.
(大地)菜緒
Daichi.
大ちゃん
Oh, that one.
そっちか~い そつ
-What's up? -Here.
(菜緒)どうしたの? (大地) これ
It's the TV drama you said you missed.
菜緒が見逃したって言ってた ドラマ
Oh, you remembered.
(菜緒) え!覚えててくれたの?
Argh! This is so frustrating.
もうイライラする
Well, until she accepts her own feelings for Uehara,
まあ上原君の件は あいつが認めない以上
it's never going to go anywhere.
始まらないだろ
Over here, Uehara! Look this way!
(女子生徒) 上原君こっち向いて
He's so handsome.
(女子生徒)かっこいい
Good morning.
おはよう
I guess he was up all night at his part-time job again.
また徹夜でバイトか
Nao.
よしかわ 仩原)吉川
Yes? What... is it?
はいな...何でしょう?
Your nose hair's sticking out.
鼻毛出てんぞ
Huh? Eek!
へ?え!
Ow. My back hurts.
(上原)ああ~背中痛い
I was just going to wash my face.
これから顔洗うところだし
-It's past noon, you know. -So what?
(上原)もう昼過ぎてんぞ (菜緒)いいじゃん
Today's a holiday.
休みなんだから
What a slacker.
だらしない奴だな
Uehara, aren't you going out today?
(菜緒)上原君 今日出かけないの?
I just got back from working at the gas station,
さっきスタンドのバイトから つご 帰ってきたばっか
and the cafe's closed today.
喫茶店のほうは 今日定休日だし
Huh? That means...
へ?…ってことは
today, Uehara and I are... alone together?
今日上原君と2人っきり?
Oh!
あつ
So what? It's no big deal.
ないない! どうってことないし
What are you doing?
(菜緒)何...何してんの!
What do you think? I'm taking a shower.
仩原)何って シャワー浴びんだよ
But I'm in here now.
(菜緒)今私使ってんの!
-Then shut your eyes for a second. -What?
仩原)じゃちょっとの間 目つぶってろよ
Wait! Stop! Stop that!
(菜緒) ちょっ…やめ…やめー!
I'm coming.
(菜緒)はーい
-Oh, Yuri-- -Excuse me.
あっ百合 (百合)ちょっとごめんね
Sorry to barge in.
お邪魔しまーす!
Yuri, what's with all the bags?
百合! 何だよその荷物
Sorry, but let me leave these here for a bit.
(百合)ごめん! ちょっとの間荷物置かせて
There's a sale going on near here, so I couldn't help buying all this.
すぐそこでバーゲンやってて ついつい買いすぎちゃつた
Ta-da!
ジャーン!
What do you think?
どう?これ
I bought this for all the year-end parties.
年末のパーティーに向けて 買っちゃつた!
It's so pretty, Yuri.
ゆりりんかわいい
Thank you, Nao. You're so sweet.
や~だ菜緒ちゃん 大好きー!
Oh, yeah. I want to give you some of my clothes.
そうだ菜緒ちゃん 今度私の服あげるね
What? Really?
えついいの?
You spend way too much on clothes.
ってか 無駄に買いすぎなんだよ
So what if I do. I earned it myself.
いいじゃない 自分で稼いだお金だし
I can use it as I please.
私の勝手でしよ
Don't talk to me like that. I'm letting you leave your bags here.
人んち荷物置き場にしといて 何だよその態度は
I bought you something too.
ちゃんと お土産買ってきたわよ 買ってきたな
Do you think I'm a child that can be pleased with--
子供じゃあるまいし そんなもんで釣られるわけ
Oh my god!
これは
That's one of the top three taiyaki shops, Medetaiya.
たい焼き御三家の1つ めで鯛家の
Waiting in line for this wasn't easy.
並ぶの大変だったな~
Whoa!
おおつ!
Before you get this, say you're sorry.
佰刽 その前に“ごめんなさい”は?
-I'm sorry. -I can't hear you.
(上原)悪かったよ (百合)聞こえなーい
-I'm sorry! -Still can't hear you.
悪かった! (百合)聞こえません
I said I'm sorry!
(上原)悪かったって!
Say, "Thank you, Yuri."
佰合) .4百合さん ありがとうございました"
Thank you.
(上原)ありがとうございました
-Say, "I really appreciate--" -Quit it. They're getting cold.
“百合さんお疲れさま" (上原)もういいよ冷めちゃうから
OK, fine.
佰刽はい!
Oh, Nao, do you want one?
あっ 菜緒ちゃんもどう?
No. I'm going to go buy something to drink.
ううん ちょっと飲み物買ってくる
Watch out!
(男性)あっぷねー!
Oh!
あっ!
Are you all right?
大丈夫ですか?
-I'm sorry. -It hurts.
ごめんなさい (一星)イッテ... いっせい
Oh...
あ… め
No!
うわあー!
$12,000!
(菜緒) 120万!? (一星)そう
to make these bowls.
有名な陶芸家に 特別に作らせた特注品なんだ
Three bowls cost $12,000. How are you going to pay for these?
3皿でしめて120万! どう落とし前つけてくれんだよ
You're kidding!
そんな...
There's no point in trying to get it from a high school kid.
(一星) とりあえず 高校生のあんたじゃ話になんない
I'll talk to your parents and get it from them.
親と直接話させてもらうから 連絡先
-No, you can't. -What?
それはダメです (一星)は?
Because of certain circumstances, I'm not living with my parents now.
今は訳があって両親とは 離れて暮らしているんです
Oh!
ハツ…
If they found out about this, they'd take me to the countryside.
このことバレたら 田舎連れてかれる!
I couldn't care less.
(一星)知らねーよそんなこと お前
Quit expecting special treatment just because you're a high school kid.
大体お前な 高校生だからって
Your problems have got nothing to do with me.
てめえの事情押し付けられても こっちは困るんだよ 凼るんに
Could I pay it off if I worked here?
じゃあここで働いて 弁償させてもらえませんか?
What?
はあ?
Let me work here, please!
ここでバイトさせてください!
Are you nuts?
(一星)お前
I'll work for the $12,000!
(菜緒) 120万円分働きます!
Dear Uehara,
(菜緒) "上原君へ,,
I just remembered something I had to do, so I won't be coming home until late.
“用事思い出したので 帰り遅くなります"
Send.
送信
I know I promised to do this, but I'm not sure I can.
あんなこと言っちゃつたけど できるのかな~
And these clothes... are hideous.
にしてもダサい
Totally hideous.
最強にダサい
He said he didn't care if these got dirty
汚していいって言ったけど 中学のジャージじゃん
The gap between Yuri and me is getting even bigger.
ますますゆりりんと 差が広がってく
Eek!
ああつ!
What the hell are you doing, you idiot?
(一星)てめえ何してんだ コノヤロー!
How many more plates are you going to break?
(一星)何皿割れば気が済むんだよ! (菜緒)すいません!
I'm in so much pain.
(菜緒)体が痛い
I never thought it would be so hard.
まさかあんなに大変だとは
I'm home.
ただいま
You sure are late.
(上原)随分遅かったな
Yeah, sorry. Huh? Where's Yuri?
(菜緒) うんちょっとね あれゆりりんは?
She left a long time ago.
(上原) とっくに帰ったよ
Oh! No!
う…うっ! うつ...
If you want some ramen, one serving is 89 cents.
(上原)ラーメン欲しいなら 袋89円な
No, thank you.
(菜緒)結構です
Where did this tree come from?
(菜緒)どうしたの?このツリ
Oh, Yuri gave it to us.
(上原)ああ百合が置いてった 口か直
It's a housewarming present.
新居祝いだとさ
Wow.
(菜緒)へえ
I told her we didn't need it because it'll get in the way.
(上原)邪魔だからいらねーって 言ったんだけど
"There is an excellent chance that whoever you spend Christmas Eve with
(まりな) ,中でも イブを一緒に過ごす相手とは"
Uehara, you're working on the 24th, right?
上原君ってさ 24日バイトだよね
Yeah. I work all night.
ああー晩中バイトだけど
-I thought so. -Huh?
(菜緒)だよね 仩原)ん?
Why do you ask?
それがどうかしたのかよ
No reason.
いや
I just thought working on Christmas Eve must be kind of lonely.
イブの日にバイトって 何か寂しいな~って思って
That's so stupid.
(上原)アホくさ 小
It's only lonely people that worry about that kind of thing.
そんなことにこだわる奴のほうが 寂しいんだよ
Who said I was worried about it?
別にこだわってなんかないし
Then why did you ask?
じゃ何で聞くんだよ
Oh... Just forget about it.
(菜緒)あーもういいよ!
What a weirdo.
変な奴
Damn him!
もう…ああ!
Ow!
(グギツ) あ…
That hurts!
いい…痛い
So you're working part-time at a ramen shop to pay it off?
(光石)弁償するために ラーメン屋でバイト?
If you spend all your time working
バイト漬けじゃ 上原君と
you'll make even less progress with Uehara.
ますます進展しないじゃん
Christmas Eve is... only ten days away.
イブまで…あと10日だよ!
How many times do I have to tell you? I've got no feeling for Uehara.
何度も言ってるけど
-There you go again. -I'm serious.
まりな) ま~たそんな (菜緒)本当だってば
I mean, he complains about everything and eats so much that it's frightening.
だっていちいちイヤミっぽいし こつ 引くほど大食いだし
When we're together, he totally looks down on me.
何か一緒にいると 見下されてる感すごいんだよね
And he makes me feel so miserable.
何か自分が みじめっていうかさ
In fact, now that I'm working, we won't have to see each other.
むしろバイトで 顔合わせなくて済むから
It's probably for the better.
そのほうがいいかも
Huh?
(菜緒)え?
"Will you spend Christmas with me?"
クリスマスを 一緒に過ごしませんか
-Really? Who's it from? -Marina!
まりな)えー!?誰誰...? (菜緒) まりな!
"I'll be waiting for you on the roof after school."
"放課後に屋上で待ってます 阿部順"
Abe Jun. Isn't he in class B?
(光石)阿部順... B組の?
-Oh, it's just Abe. -Huh?
な~んだあべっちか (菜緒)え?
He's finally gotten around to Nao.
(まりな) ついに菜緒にもきたか~
Do you know him?
(菜緒) まりな この人知ってんの?
Yeah.
(まりな) うん
Oh!
あっ!
I've got a great idea.
いいこと思いついた
We'll tell Uehara...
上原君に…
Nao.
(阿部)吉川さん
Uhm...
あの…
I like you. I've always been attracted to you.
好きです! ずっと見てました!
Please spend Christmas Eve with me.
僕と一緒に イブを過ごしませんか?
Uhm, when I see you, Nao,
いや僕 吉川さんのこと見てると
-I feel like I want to protect you.
(阿部·菜緒)守ってあげたいって 思うんですよね
Huh?
(阿部)え?
My friend just told me about you.
さっき友達から聞きました
You always tell the girls the same thing.
いつもそうやって 告白してるって
-The king of the love confession? -That's right.
(光石)告白大王? まりな)そう 大う
Abe's famous among some of the girls.
(まりな)あべっちは べつ 一部の女子の間じゃ有名なの は有 ちゃ つじ
He's always falling in love.
ほれっぽいうえに 好きになった子に
Every girl he falls for, he texts, then they all turn him down.
ことごとくメール送って 告白してはフラれてる奴
Is he really that unpopular?
(光石) そんなモテない奴なのか?
Well...
(まりな) うーん
He's not that bad looking.
まあ見た目は まあまあなんだけど
But he's not the type you'd want as a boyfriend.
彼氏にするなら 問題アリだからね
Nao would never go with a guy like that.
そんな奴菜緒だって もちろん無理だろ
-But we can use him. -We can?
まりな)でも利用価値はある (光石)ん?
Oh! Uehara!
(まりな)あっ上原君!
Wait! Wait! Uehara!
!ちょっと ちよつ 上原君!
Please.
(阿部)お願いします!
I know you may not believe me,
信じてくんないかも しんないけど など
but I do like you, Nao.
俺吉川さんのこと いいなって思ったのは確かだから
No. I'm sorry.
ごめんなさい
You mean it's true that you and Uehara are dating?
まさかあの上原と 付き合ってるって噂本当?
What? Uh...
え?あ…
Well, yes.
ん~まあ...
This world just isn't fair.
世の中不公平だよな
He's handsome, smart and good at sports.
あいつはイケメンで 頭も良くて運動もできて
He attracts girls without even trying.
女又 努力しなくても 女が寄ってきてさ
He hasn't got a worry in the world.
悩みなんて無縁だろうし
Uehara has a lot of worries.
上原君は苦しい思い たくさんしているよ
Really? He does?
そうなのか?
Uh-huh.
うん
He's got a couple of jobs so he can earn living expenses.
それにバイト掛け持ちして 生活費稼いで
But he doesn't even think
それなのに 自分が特別苦労してるなんて
that he's got it harder than anyone else.
全然思ってないの
He may look selfish, but he's always thinking of others.
わがままに見えて 実は人のことすっごい考えてて
Oh, I see.
(阿部)そっか
But I'm still jealous of Uehara.
やっぱ上原がうらやましいよ
Really?
え?
There's nobody I know
俺のこと そんなふうに言ってくれる人
Yes, there is. I'm certain there is.
いる!絶対いるよ!
One day you'll meet someone
あべっちじゃなきゃ ダメって人
But I'm not that person.
でもそれは私じゃないから
I'm sorry.
ごめんなさい
Look.
見て菜緒 生まれて初めて告白されたの
But she has no choice but to turn him down.
でもああやって 断るしかないの
Why?
え?
Here at school,
だってこの学校では
everyone thinks you and she are dating.
上原君と付き合ってることに なつてるから よつ
If she told him OK,
もしオーケーして 二股かけてるなんて噂立ったら
Imagine the punishment she'd get from your fans.
上原君のファンに ひどい目に遭わされるでしょ?
And although she tries to spend Christmas Eve with other friends,
イブの予定入れようにも 彼氏持ちってことで
they wouldn't let her join since she has a boyfriend.
友達にも相手にされないし
She's only doing it because she's away from her family
ただでさえ 家族と離れてて寂しいのに
Isn't that right, Mitsuishi?
ねえみつちゃん
Yeah.
(光石)ああ
In fact, Marina and I've got plans for Christmas Eve already.
実は俺らも イブは用事があって
So we can't spend it with her.
緒にいてやれないんだ
You know, I'm glad I talked to you, Nao.
(阿部) 何か吉川と話せてよかった
I'm going to work hard at developing a real relationship.
俺ちゃんと恋愛できるように 頑張ってみる
-Good. -Bye.
(菜緒) うん (阿部) じゃあ
What a pity.
(まりな)あ~あ
She had to destroy a chance that she'll never have again.
二度とないチャンスを 潰しちゃつた
So, it would be kind of nice, you know,
だから上原君には 少~しだけ菜緒に
if you showed just a little kindness to Nao.
優しくしてあげてほしいな~ な~ hK
Of course Christmas Eve is special for girls.
(ななこ)そりゃあ 女にとってイブは特別よ
-It is? -You see, girls just love
(上原)そうなのか? はない女なんて
dressing up, feeling a thrill, and experiencing love over and over again.
おしゃれときめき恋 その繰り返し
Christmas Eve is all that wrapped into one.
イブはその集大成だもん
Spending it all alone is like
ひとりぼっちで過ごす イブなんて って
God telling you that you're a failure as a woman.
神様に女として失格って 言われてるようなもんよ
It's hard to believe you're still in junior high.
(上原)お前本当に中3かよ
So right now
だから
all the girls are in a mad dash to avoid spending it alone.
ひとりぼっちはこの時期 みーんなラストスパートね
A mad dash?
ラストスパート?
What I mean is they're going to parties and looking for a partner.
つまり相手を求めて コンパ三昧
-What? -Boys are the same, right?
仩原)はあ? (ななこ)男だってそうでしょ? こつ
Lately, even I've been asked out by a lot of guys.
今の時期になると 私もアプローチがすごくって
-Could it be... -But there's already this guy I like.
もしかして
That's why she's been coming home so late recently?
あいつそれで 最近帰りが遅いのか? 取近滯
For the time being, I can only work at night.
バイトしばらくは 夜だけ入って
But even if I work all day after winter break starts on the 24th...
24日から冬休み それ以降は終日働けるとして
Ah...
(菜緒)あ~
How long will it take to pay back the $12,000?
120万なんていつ返せんだか
Oh... I know what to do.
あ…そうだ
Mom.
お母さん
No, no, no... I've got to deal with this myself.
いやいや… 自分で何とかしなきゃ
Nine dollars an hour...
時給900円
If I work eight hours a day...
1日8時間働けるとして
What? That's all I'll make?
え…これだけ?
No!
ああ~
Oh, dear.
ああ...
What should I do?
どうしよう
It'll never happen. I don't know what to do.
無理だよ どうしよう
Ahh... I can't handle this.
ああ...もうやだ
-Thank you. -Thank you for coming.
(客)ごちそうさま (菜緒)ありがとうございました!
Here we are. Here's your miso ramen.
はーいみそラーメン お待たせしました
It's such a pleasure seeing your smiling face, Nao.
いやあ菜緒ちゃんの 笑顔見ると癒やされるよ
Oh, come on. Give me a break.
えーそんなことないです
Excuse me. Could I get some water?
すいませ-ん 水ください
Sure. I'll be there in a second.
はーいただいま!
In spite of everything, she's fitting right in.
(一星)何だかんだ 板についてきたな
Why don't you take a quick break, Nao?
(徹平)菜緒ちゃん 少しは休憩したら?
Well...
(菜緒)でも
I just don't feel right not working.
何か動いてないと 申し訳なくて
I mean, I broke seven dishes in three days
だって3日間で こつ お皿7枚と 3枚
and I wasted five bowls of ramen.
ラーメン5杯 無駄にしちゃつたし
It's no big deal at all.
そんなの全然 大したことないから
Yes, it is a big deal, Dad.
いや大したことあるぞ
-Welcome. -Hi, Nao.
(菜緒)いらっしゃいませ~ (まりな)菜緒
Marina. Mitsuishi. You came.
(菜緒) まりなみつちゃん 来てくれたんだね!
Look at you, Nao.
(光石)菜緒何かこう
That's one crazy outfit.
すごい格好だな
But it oddly suits her.
でも不思議なほど なじんでる
Well...
(菜緒) うん
I hate to admit it, but I agree.
悔しいけど 私もそう思うんだよね
Actually, we've brought along a special guest.
実はもう1人 スペシャルゲストが来てます
Really?
え!
-We really just ran into him outside. -Don't say that.
(光石) っていうかさつき そこで偶然会っただけだろ
Yo.
おう
Daichi.
大ちゃん!
Let's eat.
いただきまーす!
We're done.
ごちそうさま
That was delicious.
おいしかった
You've got quite an appetite, miss.
お姉さん いい食べっぷりだね
Oh, wow! What a nice looking guy!
なになにいい男じゃん!
-That's Issei, the bully. -I see.
(菜緒)あれが Sの一星さん まりな)ふ~ん ド
Call me Icchan.
(一星) "いっちゃん”でいいよ
All the customers do.
お客さん みんなそう呼ぶし
That was really good, Icchan.
いっちゃんごちそうさま~
It's really hard to believe Nao's working a part-time job.
それにしても菜緒が バイトなんてな
She believed in Santa Claus until she was a sixth grader.
小6までサンタクロース 信じてたのに
What? Seriously?
え?マジで?
Every year, my dad dressed up as Santa for Nao's sake.
(大地)毎年うちの親父が 菜緒のためにサンタの格好してさ
It wasn't easy for me to act like I was happy too.
俺まで喜ぶフリすんの 大変だったよ
You sure have a knack for making people fret over you.
(光石)お前どんだけ 人に気使わせてんだよ
Sorry.
(菜緒)ごめん
It just shows how happy it made us to see your reaction.
それほど菜緒のリアクションが うれしかったんだよ
She would get all excited over each little present.
プレゼントも いちいち大喜びだったし
That's right. Ever since I was little,
そうそう子供の頃から 大ちゃんが選んでくれる
I liked the prize more than the candy it came with.
お菓子は中身よりも おまけ
I liked the picture on the box more than the game inside.
ゲームなら内容よりも 絵柄
He always knew exactly what would please me.
いっつも私のツボ 押さえててくれてさ
Nao!
吉川! いつまで油売ってんだ
-Get going. -Sorry.
早くしろ (菜緒)すいません
Enjoy yourselves.
みんなゆっくりしててね
-Nao. -Yes?
(大地なあ (菜緒)ん?
If you don't have any plans for Christmas Eve,
(大地)今年のイブも何もなかったら 一緒に過ごすか?
You can get it off from the ramen shop, right?
いや…ラーメン屋のバイト イプなら休めるんだろ?
Yeah. It is a yearly tradition, after all.
(菜緒) うん毎年恒例だもんね
I look forward to your mom's juicy hamburger steaks.
おばさんが作る煮込みハンバーグ 楽しみだな こな
This year, why don't we spend it alone together?
今年は2人で どっか出かけないか
Huh?
(菜緒)え?
The family party is fine,
ホームパーティーもいいけど
but I thought you'd like that kind of thing better, Nao.
菜緒がよかったら そういうのもいいかなって よつ
-You don't have-- -Shh!
まあ気楽に (菜緒)シーツ
Go!
5 25 2...
What's wrong?
どうした?
Is that Uehara?
上原?
I don't want him to see me like this.
(菜緒)絶対こんな姿 見られたくない
Don't you dare tell Uehara that I'm working this job.
大ちゃんバイトのこと 上原君に絶対言わないでね
OK.
おう...
Whew.
ハアハア..
Thank goodness. Let's go.
よかった 行くよ
Ow!
(EIA) TT y T y T...
Hey, Nao!
おい吉川! の
How many times have I told you to pick up your stuff?
散らかすなって あれほど言っただろ
Hey... Wake up.
(上原) おい 寝てんじゃねーよ
I'm home.
ただいま…
Hi. Welcome back.
(上原)おうおかえり
You OK?
大丈夫か?
I'm fine. Just a little tired.
大丈夫 ちょっと疲れちゃつて
Such a nice smell.
いい匂いがする
Huh?
え
Pork soup base with Japanese broth.
とんこつベースに 和風ダシがきいた
Ah! Hey!
あ…うおつ !
Cut that out.
5 25 2...
I'm tired.
つ...疲れた
First I'll take a bath.
先お風呂入るから
Oh, would you like to go somewhere on the 24th?
あつ24日どっか行くか?
What?
え?
I got the day off from work.
バイト休み取れたから
Did you hear me?
聞いてんのか
Oh... Yes, I see.
あ…うんそっか
OK... Where are we going?
じゃ...どこ行く?
Where should we go?
ど…どこ行こっか
Oh... We could have dinner here.
あ…ご飯 ここでもいい?
Then we could see the Christmas lights and take a walk.
その後イルミネーション見て ささ…散歩してさ
OK, that's it. That's what we'll do.
じゃそれじゃあ… そういうことで
What's with her?
何だよ
Yes!
やったー!
"Would you like to go somewhere on the 24th?
(上原のマネ) 24日どっか行くか?
I got the day off from work."
バイト休み取れたから
Yes! Yes!
やったやった つたやつ
Ow! Ow!
(ぶつかる音) 小 (菜緒)い...痛いイッ…
Yes! Well done!
(まりな)いや~よくやった!
I can hardly believe it! You're spending Christmas Eve
我が校が誇る激レア ハイクラスのイケメン
with our school's pride and joy, a super-rare, high-class stud.
上原君と イブを過ごすなんて!
Uehara just happened to get the day off from work.
だからたまたま 上原君のバイトの休みが取れて
He just kind of wondered if I wanted to go somewhere, I think.
だったらどっか行こうかって つ1こ ノリ?
I don't particularly care if we do or not.
私はまあ どっちでもよかったんだけどさ
Yeah, yeah. Whatever, whatever.
はいはい 分かった分かった
You can finally move on from Daichi, huh?
ついに大地先輩からは 卒業か
Oh, no!
あっ!
Daichi is at a training camp until tomorrow.
(信彦)大地なら 明日まで遠征合宿だけど
Oh, I see. Thank you.
そうですか ありがとうございます
I think it'll be fine.
まあいいんじゃないの?
Daichi did say, "If you don't have any plans," right?
大ちゃんも“何にもなかったら”って 言ってたんでしょ?
Yes.
(菜緒) うん
But he said he wanted to spend it alone together this year.
でも今年は 2人で過ごそうって言ってたしな
He just means spending it together like siblings would, right?
そんなの兄妹が一緒に過ごす みたいな感覚でしょ?
I mean, Daichi is one of the top three studs.
大ちゃんだって こつ イケメン御三家の1人だよ?
He could easily find someone to spend Christmas Eve with.
本当ならいくらでもイブを 緒に過ごす相手いるんだから
In fact, I'm surprised you've been friends for ten years.
逆によく10年も お前の相手してきたよな~
Anyway, I'll keep trying to get hold of him.
とりあえず こまめに連絡してみる
Oh, wow! I am so happy for you.
ああ~ ! それにしてもうれしい
The day is coming soon
上原君の彼女のフリのつもりが 現実になる日も近いかもよ
I knew it. You're faking it.
(阿部) やっぱりフリだったんだな
Huh?
(まりな)ん?
Whoa, Abe!
(光石)おお阿部順!
-Where'd you come from? -Listen.
いつの間に (阿訒俺 口
I haven't been able to get Nao out of my head.
あれから吉川さんのことが 頭から離れなくて
My, you're unusually slow getting over it this time.
珍しく切り替え遅いね あべっち
How could it possibly be true?
どう考えても おかしいと思ったんだよ
There's no way you're dating Uehara.
あの上原と付き合ってるなんて
Nao, I don't know why you're doing it
吉川さんどんな事情があったか 分かんないけど
but don't you feel it's meaningless to fake being Uehara's girlfriend?
吉川さんは 上原の彼女のフリなんて
Aah!
(まりな)あー!
How about you and I go to a party on Christmas Eve, OK?
イブは私とコンパに行こう ねっ!
There'll be swarms of cute girls there.
かわいい子わんさか来るから
-Well, I'd rather-- -Shut up.
(阿部)いやでも俺は... まりな) うるさい よ)つる
How pretty.
かわいい
What?
ええつ!?
$390.
359千円
That's so expensive.
高い
Oh, Yuri.
あ…ゆりりん!
What are you up to?
何してんの?
-Ah... -Yes?
(菜緒)あ 佰刽ん? あん )ノ)ノ
Yep, I think this one suits you best.
(百合) うんやっぱり これが一番似合うわね
-But-- -Don't you like it?
(菜緒)あの (百合)気に入らない? のに )ノ)ノ
OK, then this is my Christmas present to you.
じゃあ私からの クリスマスプレゼントってことで
Really?
(菜緒)え?
No, I can't take this--
いやタダでもらうわけには..
It's one of my old ones, so don't worry about it.
私のお古だから気にしないで
Are you sure it's OK?
本当にいいの?
Uh-huh.
佰合) うん
Now, as for the food, he likes meat.
料理の件だけど 久志は肉好きだけど
But as for soup, he likes seafood.
スープは シーフード系がいいみたいよ
He likes any kind of pasta.
パスタは全種類オーケーね
I see...
(菜緒) うん
The soup should be seafood.
スープはシーフードね
OK, got it.
うんよし
Oh... but I'm not really...
あ…いや私は
There's no need to play dumb, Nao.
もうとぼけても無駄よ 菜緒ちゃん
I can see you're in love. It's written all over your face.
恋してるって顔に書いてある
But what's the point in admitting that I am?
でも認めても仕方ないし
Why do you say that?
どうして?
You know what I'm talking about, Yuri.
ゆりりんも知ってるでしょ?
You told me his heart isn't so easily moved.
簡単には 上原君の心は動かないって よいつ
That's true.
確かに…
but if he made you his girlfriend
でもだからこそ
that's exactly why he'd treat you with very special care.
彼女になったら すごく大事にしてもらえると思うよ
Hi.
上原)どうも
Can you give Nao a message?
(大地) 菜緒に伝言頼んでいいかな
Tell her I'll come get her tomorrow, Christmas Eve, just past noon.
明日のイブ昼過ぎに 迎えに行くって
Tomorrow, Christmas Eve?
明日のイブ?
That's right.
そう
Our families get together every year on Christmas Eve.
イブは毎年 家族ぐるみで過ごしてたけど
But I've decided she and I would spend it together this year.
今年は2人で過ごすって 決めたんだ
I've decided that's how it will be from now on.
俺はこれからは そうするって決めたんだ
Later.
(大地) じゃあな やめな
Welcome home.
おかえり
So, about tomorrow, I was thinking of having dinner early.
ねえ明日のイブなんだけどさ 夕食早めにしようと思うんだけど
Nah, I've got work tomorrow.
(上原)やっぱ俺 バイト入れたから
OK, then I'll have it ready by six o'clock tomor...
(菜緒) うん ゃあ 明日6時に支度して じ
What?
ええつ!?
Hey!
(菜緒)ちょっ
What did you just say?
今何て?
I've got work tomorrow.
俺明日バイト入れたから
But... Why?
だから…何でよ
You already had something planned, right?
だってお前 こつ 先約あったんだろ
You should have told me you were doing something with that senior.
あの先輩と そうならそうと言えよな
Senior? You mean Daichi?
先輩って…大ちゃん?
I plan on turning down Daichi--
大ちゃんなら断るつもりで
You celebrated with him every year, right?
毎年一緒に 祝ってたんだろ?
There is no point for me to go out of my way
なら俺がわざわざ
Worry over me?
気を使うって
You invited me out because you were worried about me?
気を使って誘ってくれたの?
On top of faking like we're dating, I've caused you other problems too.
付き合ってるフリしてる以上 いろいろ迷惑かけてたかなって
What's that supposed to mean? What makes you think you're responsible?
何それ 勝手に責任感じないでよ
What? Weren't you panicking over it?
はあ? でも焦ってたんじゃないのかよ
Along with that girl, Marina,
あのまりなって子と
weren't you looking for a date for Christmas Eve?
一緒にイブを過ごす相手 探してたんじゃないの?
What? No, I wasn't.
は?そんなことしてないよ
Then...
じゃあ
why have you been coming home so late recently?
何で最近 帰りが遅かったんだよ
Well...
tha...
Well what?
何だよ
I had work.
バイト
Work? Where?
バイトってどこで?
At a cafe... near the station.
駅前の…カフェ
You look like you're lying.
目が泳いでるし
I'm not.
違うよ
Well, I don't really understand it,
俺にはよく分かんねーけど
but Christmas Eve is special to girls, right?
女にとってイブは 特別なんだろ?
You bet it is. It's very special.
(菜緒)そうだよ 特別だよ
It's a day you spend having fun and eating cake
恋人でも家族でも 大切に思える人と
It can't be just anyone. It matters who you spend it with.
でも誰でもいいからって 一緒にいたい日じゃないよ!
Then... it must be nice having him around.
だからよかったな あの人いて
Oh, just forget it!
もういいよ!
What's with her?
何だよ...
Dammit!
もう!
Let's ask these people.
(リポーター) 聞いてみたいと思います
Merry Christmas.
メリークリスマス!
-Merry Christmas.
(カップル)
-You're all couples, right? -Yes.
(リポーター)皆さんはカップルで いらっしゃいますよね
How sweet. We asked people on the street
(リポーター) いいですね さあそこで街行く皆さんに
who they would be spending Christmas Eve with.
クリスマスを一緒に過ごす お相手を
The number one answer was, of course, with a sweetheart.
1位はやはりこちら
How pretty.
きれい
Uehara...
上原君…
Daichi.
大ちゃん
I heard your message turning me down, but you sounded kind of depressed.
断りの留守電聞いたんだけど 何か声元気なさそうだったから
Oh, yeah... I'm sorry.
そっか…ごめんね
Did I cause you trouble?
迷惑だった?
No. Come on in.
ううん 上がって
Merry Christmas.
(ななこ)メリークリスマス!
How about a delicious,
おいしい手作りの
-homemade Christmas cake? -Please be careful with the box.
クリスマスケーキは いかがですか?
Thank you very much.
(明)ありがとうございました
Are you sure you want to work? You had the day off.
(明)本当によかったの?上原君 せっかくの休みだったのに
Of course it's OK.
そりゃあやっぱ 久志君だって こつ
Who do you mean by "someone special"?
何だその 大切な人って言うのは
Oh.
(ななこ)あ
How about a Christmas cake?
クリスマスケーキ いかがですか?
It's very special.
僳綯特別だよ
It's a day you spend having fun and eating cake
大切に思える人と
with the people who are special to you, whether it's a sweetheart or family.
ケーキ囲んで 幸せに過ごす日だよ
It can't be just anyone. It matters who you spend it with.
でも誰でもいいからって 一緒にいたい日じゃないよ!
Sorry... that I'm not someone special.
悪かったな 大切じゃなくて
I can't believe it.
rSV...
Thirty-eight point five degrees?
38度5分!?
How could you not notice? You can be so dense sometimes.
自分で気づかないなんて どんだけ鈍感なんだよ
I've really been pushing myself lately.
最近ずっと 気張ってたから
-Here. -Thank you.
休地はい (菜緒)ありがとう はあ 大︶
I'll make you some porridge, but is there anything else you'd like?
おかゆ作るけど 何か他に食べたい物ある?
A cake.
ケーキ
You can have cake after you get over this cold.
ケーキは 風邪治ってからにしろよ
I want to eat a nice, round cake.
丸いケーキが食べたい
The typical strawberry cake
大ちゃんちで よく出してくれてた
that we always had at your house.
ベタな苺のケーキ
We'd all sit around it, laughing and singing.
でみんなで囲んで 歌って笑って
Thank you, Daichi.
大ちゃんありがとね
Huh?
ん?
For spending it with me every year.
毎年付き合ってくれて
Thanks to you,
おかげで今まで イブが寂しいなんて
Thank you.
(上原)ありがとうございました
One cake, please.
ケーキ1つください
OK.
(上原)はい
Nao says she wants to eat one... like this.
菜緒が食べたいっていうから これ
That'll be $33.
3300円です
I've always known pretty much everything that Nao likes.
俺昔から菜緒が好きなものは 分かるんだ
What?
は?
On Christmas, she likes chicken and potage soup.
クリスマスは チキンとポタージュスープ
She likes that really typical stuff.
そういうベタなのが 好きなんだあいつは
Why are you telling me this?
何が言いたいんすか?
But today, she prepared rolled cabbage and seafood soup.
でも今日は
Even though she's sick, she went out of her way to make them.
体壊してるのに 無理して作って待ってんだよ
What are you trying to tell me?
だから何言ってんだよ
She's not the type to complain.
(大地)あいつ弱音吐かねえんだ
She never has been.
昔つから
But she's got a fever now, and said she's lonely.
でも熱出して 寂しいって言ってた
Huh?
え
If you made her a promise, then you'd better keep it.
度約束したんなら守れよ
You're the greatest, Daichi.
(幼少の菜緒)大ちゃん大好き!
Open your eyes.
(幼少の大地)いいよ
Wow! It's a Hokkori Man sticker.
(幼少の菜緒) うわあ! ホッコリマンチョコのシールだ
I thought you'd like it.
菜緒が欲しいと思って
How did you know?
どうして分かったの?
I just know. I know everything you like, Nao.
俺分かるもん 菜緒の好きなもの全部
You're the greatest, Daichi!
大ちゃんだ~い好き!
Nao. I'm coming in.
吉川 入るぞ
Uehara.
(菜緒)上原君
Lie back down.
(上原)寝てろ
What about your work?
(菜緒)バイトは?
I took off
(上原)あがらせてもらったよ
after hearing what he had to say.
あの人から知らせ聞いて
Who? Daichi?
(菜緒)あの人って... 大ちゃん?
Nao.
吉川
Yes?
(菜緒)何?
I know you've got a fever now, but...
熱出してる時に 何なんだけど
Huh?
あれ
Oh... uh...
あ…あ...
That's...
Entd....
for my job... at the ramen shop.
ラーメン屋のバイトの
Ramen shop?
ラーメン屋!?
You mean you weren't working at a cafe near the station.
駅前のカフェじゃ なかったのかよ
No.
(菜緒) うん
Why did you make up such a stupid thing?
何だよ何でそんな くだらねーウソつくんだよ
-I couldn't help it. -Why?
(菜緒)だって (上原)何だよ
Sometimes you don't want people to see you looking a certain way.
人には見られたくない姿 ってもんがあるでしよう
Why?
仩原)はあ?
If you saw me delivering ramen when I was dressed like this,
このジャージで ラーメン運んだら
you'd make fun of me.
バカにするでしょ
Yeah, it is pretty awful looking.
プッ 確かにひでえな フフフ確かにひでぇな
That outfit... isn't anything to brag about either.
そっちも その格好も言えないと思うけど
What?
仩原)え?
Stop laughing.
うるせー な
You're the only one that I didn't want to see me like that.
上原君だけには 見られたくなかったから
Why?
え?
I mean, we see each other every day.
だって こつ 毎日顔合わせるしさ
I'm adding one more rule to the list.
同居のルールに1つ追加だ
Really?
え?
Don't put on an act. Lean on others when you need to.
カッコつけんな 頼るところは頼れ
I could have helped you and prevented you from getting sick.
体壊す前に 俺も助けようがあったし
Who was it that collapsed the other day?
この前倒れたのは どこの誰でしたか?
That's not important. Are you going to follow the rules?
つつ うつせえ いいから返事
Yes.
は~い
Oh!
あつ
-Is that a cake? -Yeah.
これケーキ? 仩原) うん
That's great. Can I look?
うれしい 見てもいい?
But no eating until your fever goes down.
食うのは 熱下がってからだぞ
OK.
うん
Uh-oh.
(EA) 5...
Crap. I shouldn't have run.
やばっ!走ったから
Hey! Don't!
あつバカ!
I said no eating.
食うなって
See. I bet you're feeling sick now, aren't you?
ほら気持ち悪くなったんだろ
No. It's delicious.
(菜緒) ううん おいしい
But if he made you his girlfriend
(百合)でもだからこそ
that's exactly why he'd treat you with very special care.
彼女になったら すごく大事にしてもらえると思うよ
I'm fine with the way things are now.
(菜緒) このままで十分
Huh?
え?
I'm fine just like this.
(菜緒)私このままで十分だよ
You can't stay like that. Your fever's still super high.
いやダメだろ まだ熱めっちゃ高いんだぞ
You're right.
だね
I'm going to have a taste of this.
(上原)いただきます
Hey!
(菜緒)ちょっと
Hey, Nao. I got some milk pudding.
(上原)おい吉川 牛乳プリン買ってきたぞ
I'm feeling better, so I'm going for a walk in the park.
(菜緒) "体調が戻ったので 公園まで散歩してきます!
Nao.
"菜緒,,
What?
はあ?
What did you want to see me for, Nao?
どうしたんだよ 吉川から呼び出すなんて
I thought I should tell you the truth, Abe.
あべっちには本当のこと 話しておきたいなって思って
You mean, you want to date me?
もしかして 俺と付き合う気になった?
It's just like you said. Uehara and I aren't dating.
私あべっちの言うとおり べつ 上原君とは付き合ってないの
Really?
(阿部)え?
Uehara doesn't have any feelings for me.
上原君は私のこと 何とも思ってないけど
Then, you mean...
じゃあ…
But...
TC to
I like Uehara.
私は上原君のことが好きなの
Huh?
え
I like... Uehara.
上原君のことが好きだから
Oh!
あつ